<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>rocs.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="et">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="nds">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Rocs</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxRocsxx</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">繪圖_Rocs</name>
  <summary>Rocs Graph Theory</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Teoria de grafs Rocs</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Rocs-Graphentheorie</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">Rocs Graph Theory</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Teoría de grafos de Rocs</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="et">Rocs graafiteooria</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Rocs-graafiteoria</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nds">Graphentheorie „Rocs“</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Rocs grafentheorie</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Teoria grafów Rocs</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Teoria dos Grafos no Rocs</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Teoria dos grafos de Rocs</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Teória grafov Rocs</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Teorija grafov Rocs</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Rocs grafteori</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Теорія графів «Rocs»</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxRocs Graph Theoryxx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-TW">Rocs 圖形理論</summary>
  <description>
    <p>Rocs is a Graph Theory IDE for designing and analyzing graph algorithms. It provides an easy to use visual editor for creating graphs, a scripting engine to execute algorithms, and several helper tools for simulations and experiments. Algorithms are specified in JavaScript.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Rocs és un EID (IDE) de Teoria de Grafs per dissenyar i analitzar algorismes de grafs. Ofereix un editor visual d'ús senzill per crear grafs, un motor de creació d'scripts per executar algorismes i diverses eines d'ajuda per simulacions i experiments. Els algorismes s'especifiquen en JavaScript.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Rocs ist eine Entwicklungsumgebung für Graphen-Theorie zur Entwicklung und Analyse von Graphen-Algorithmen. Es enthält einen einfach zu bedienenden Editor für die Erstellung von Datenstrukturen, ein leistungsfähiges Skriptmodul zur Ausführung von Algorithmen und mehrere Hilfswerkzeuge für Simulationen und Experimente. Algorithmen werden in JavaScript geschrieben.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Rocs is a Graph Theory IDE for designing and analysing graph algorithms. It provides an easy to use visual editor for creating graphs, a scripting engine to execute algorithms, and several helper tools for simulations and experiments. Algorithms are specified in JavaScript.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Rocs es una interfaz de desarrollo integrado sobre la teoría de grafos que permite diseñar y analizar algoritmos de gafos. Proporciona un editor visual muy fácil de usar para crear grafos, un motor de guiones para ejecutar algoritmos y varias herramientas auxiliares para realizar simulaciones y experimentar. Los algoritmos se especifican en JavaScript.</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Rocs on graafiteooria arenduskeskkond, milles saab luua ja analüüsida graafialgoritme. Rakendus pakub hõlpsasti kasutatavat visuaalset redaktorit graafide loomiseks, skriptimootorit algoritmide täitmiseks ning mitmeid abistavaid tööriistu simulatsioonideks ja eksperimentideks. Algoritmid on kirjutatud JavaScriptis.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Rocs on graafiteoria-IDE (integroitu kehitysympäristö) graafialgoritmien suunnitteluun ja analysointiin. Siinä on visuaalinen muokkain graafien luontiin, skriptausmoottori algoritmien suorittamiseen sekä useita aputyökaluja simulaatioita ja kokeita varten. Algoritmit kirjoitetaan JavaScriptillä.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nds">Rocs is en Graphensmeed, dor laat sik Graphen mit opstellen un analyseren. De visuelle Editor för de Graphen lett sik eenfach bruken, dat gifft en Skriptkarn för Algoritmen un en Reeg Hülpprogrammen för Simuleren un Experimenten. Algoritmen warrt in JavaScript opstellt.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Rocs is een IDE voor de grafentheorie, voor het ontwerpen en analyseren van graafalgoritmes. Het bevat een eenvoudig te gebruiken visueel bewerkingsprogramma voor het aanmaken van grafen, een scriptprogramma voor het laten werken van algoritmes, en wat hulpmiddelen voor simulaties en experimenten. Algoritmes worden geschreven in JavaScript.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Rocs jest IDE teorii grafów do tworzenia i analizowania algorytmów grafów. Dostarcza łatwy w użyciu edytor wizualny do tworzenia grafów, silnik skryptów do wykonywania algorytmów i kilka innych narzędzi pomocniczych do symulacji i eksperymentów. Algorytmy są pisane w JavaScript.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Rocs é um IDE de teoria do grafos para desenhar e analisar algoritmos de grafos. Oferece um editor visual simples de usar para criar grafos, um motor de programação para executar os algoritmos e diversas ferramentas auxiliares para as simulações e experiências. Os algoritmos são definidos em JavaScript.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Rocs é um ambiente de teoria do grafos para desenhar e analisar algoritmos de grafos. Oferece um editor visual simples de usar para criação de grafos, um mecanismo de criação de scripts para executar algoritmos e diversas ferramentas auxiliares para simulações e experimentos. Os algoritmos são definidos em JavaScript.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Rock je integrované prostredie pre teóriu grafov na návrh a analýzu grafových algoritmov. Obsahuje jednoducho použiteľný vizuálny editor na tvorbu grafov, skriptovací engine a spúšťanie algoritmov a niekoľko pomocných nástrojov na simulácie a experimenty. Algoritmy sú špecifikované v JavaScripte.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Rocs je integrirano razvojno okolje za oblikovanje in preučevanje algoritmov grafov. Ponuja preprost grafični urejevalnik za ustvarjanje grafov, skriptni pogon za izvajanje algoritmov in pomagalnike za simulacije in poskuse. Algoritme pišete v JavaScript.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Rocs är en grafteoretisk integrerad utvecklingsmiljö för att skapa och analysera grafalgoritmer. Den tillhandahåller en lättanvänd visuell editor för att skapa grafer, ett skriptgränssnitt för att exekvera algoritmer och flertalet hjälpverktyg för simuleringar och experiment. Algoritmer definieras med Javascript.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Rocs — інтегроване середовище розробки (IDE) графів, призначене для створення та аналізу алгоритмів для графів. У середовищі передбачено простий у користуванні візуальний редактор для створення графів, рушій для виконання алгоритмів та декілька допоміжних інструментів для імітацій та експериментів. Мовою для запису алгоритмів є діалект JavaScript.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxRocs is a Graph Theory IDE for designing and analyzing graph algorithms. It provides an easy to use visual editor for creating graphs, a scripting engine to execute algorithms, and several helper tools for simulations and experiments. Algorithms are specified in JavaScript.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">Rocs 是一套圖形理論的整合介面環境，用來設計與分析圖形演算法。它提供一套易用的視覺編輯器，用來建立圖形；一套文稿引擎用來執行演算法；還有一些協助工具用來模擬與實驗 JavaScript 的 演算法。</p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://edu.kde.org/rocs/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=rocs</url>
  <url type="help">http://docs.kde.org/stable/en/kdeedu/rocs/index.html</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>http://kde.org/images/screenshots/rocs.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>rocs</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
